Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

ABHISHEK TRIPATHI (1) Featured

Cloud & Software Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Java, J2Ee, Hibernate, Spring, Log4j, Maven, IntelliJ, JUnit, Apache Tomcat.NoSQL



Current Designation: Cloud and Software Engineer 2 Total Experience: 0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Dell EMC

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

SDLC, Bug Fixing

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Cloud & Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program

Management, Project Management, Requirement

Gathering, Java, J2Ee, Hibernate, Spring, Log4j, Maven, IntelliJ, JUnit, Apache Tomcat, NoSQL SDLC, Bug Fixing

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21 Last Active: 21-Jan-21

Summary

A focused professional; offering 3.5 years of experience in Designing, Development, Implementing, and Debugging Software/Applications

Currently associated with Dell EMC, Bengaluru, Karnataka as Cloud and Software Engineer 2; working on project titled CloudIQ to gather a matrix of different servers manufactured by Dell EMC for customer and internal monitoring

Actively participating in the architectural design of the CloudIQ and it's different components

Skilled in working on Distributed Systems Architecture comprising different micro-services written in Java and Python Skilled in Backend Software Development including Cloud Technology

Kaleidoscope Project: Used for cluster analysis and comprised different independent components written in Java, Python, Node.js.

Developed Feedback Tool using the Server-less (AWS lambda) and Java

Work Experience

Dell EMC as Cloud and Software Engineer 2

Feb 2019 to Till Date

Developing micro-services to subscribe/poll the data from different sources (i.e. Dell EMC products), administering preprocessing and dumping the same into time-series database

Serving the data to users via different Adapters written in Java and plugins written in Angular.js

Analyzing & developing software/application solutions by studying information needs, conferring with users, studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes

Mapping client's requirements and providing effective solutions involving evaluation and definition of scope of project and finalization of requirements

Implementing the project as per scheduled deadlines; extending post-implementation & maintenance support to the technical support team and client

Documenting software solutions through flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments, and clear code

Providing information related to software bugs & defects by collecting, analyzing, and summarizing development & service issues and rendering assistance in troubleshooting the same

Establishing & maintaining healthy business relations with clients and ensuring high customer satisfaction matrices by achieving delivery & service quality norms

Rendering assistance in analysis of Business/System Requirements Documents and Use Cases, RTM, Test Planning, Effort Estimation, Task Allocation, Monitoring, & Reviewing Escalation, Prioritization, Test Scripting, Test Execution, Defect Identification & Management, Reporting, and preparation of Test Summary Report

IG Infotech India Pvt. Ltd as Graduate Trainee - Associate Developer Nov 2017 to Feb 2019

Associate Developer:

Successfully developed the Enterprise Message Bus Framework for the Kafka, Kafka Producer, and Kafka Consumer Devised the DLQ Framework for the Apache ActiveMQ; added ACL's (Access Control List) in the Enterprise Message Bus Framework in order to enable the Producer/Consumer only consume from the Kafka topics Graduate Trainee:

Drove measures to develop:

o Logging framework for ELK to log the messages in the format (JSON format) specified by Architects and Business o Kafka Load Simulator which generated the AVRO messages of specified AVRO Schema to test load managed by Kafka Wrote logic for Embedded Kafka to run the integration test cases and Quartz Scheduler for Scheduling the snapshot received from the upstream Application

ATMECS Technologies as Software Engineer

Mar 2017 to Nov 2017

Successfully developed Big Data Solution for the capacity management of the Hadoop and Non-Hadoop machines Created the connectors for HPE cloud to decide the prices and create the Event API & Pricing API

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Hindustan Institute of Technology and Management, Agra, Uttar Pradesh in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

C-DAC Diploma in Advance Computing

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java, J2EE, Python, SQL,NoSQL, HTML, CSS			
Grafana			
Splunk, ELK Elastic Search, Logstash			
Kibana			
MySQL, MongoDB, Influx DB			
AWS Lambda (Serverless)			
Eclipse, IntelliJ, Pycharm			
TDD, Agile			
Ubuntu Server, Apache Tomcat			
Maven, Git, Bamboo, Jenkins, Terraform			
Spring, Spring Boot			
Java Collections framework			
Multithreading, REST API, JUnit			
Spring Integration, Apache Kafka			
Hibernate, Apache ActiveMQ			
Apache Log4j, Apache Avro, Apache Hadoop			
Apache POI, Apache Ambari, RabbitMQ			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time